Inventory of the Jean Henry Large miscellaneous papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Jean Henry Large miscellaneous papers
1850-1962
66028
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Writings, a diary, correspondence, and photographs, relating to the genealogy of the Henry family and to personal affairs of Jean Henry Large and Lou Henry Hoover.
Large, Jean Henry.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1966.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collection
Berton W. Crandall photographs, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical/Historical Note
Jean Henry Large was born in 1882 in Waterloo, Iowa to Florence Weed and Charles Delano Henry. She was the younger sister of Lou Henry Hoover, wife of Herbert Hoover. She lived for a brief time in Hawaii and worked as a writer. She died in 1958.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers relate to the genealogy of the Henry family and to personal affairs of Jean Henry Large and Lou Henry Hoover. The papers are comprised of writings, a diary, correspondence, photographs, and printed matter. Some items are photocopies.
Henry family.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hoover, Lou Henry, 1874-1944.
- Correspondence, 1912; 1941
  - Letter from Lou Henry to Jean Henry, undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Physical Description
    Photocopy and typed copy
  - Letter to Jean Henry re Pearl Harbor attack, 1941 December 8 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Postcards to Charles D. Henry, 1912 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Diary of Jean Henry, 1901 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  Photocopy
  Scope and Contents note
  Describes activities with Lou Henry in Yokohama, Japan
- Miscellany, 1923-1962
  - Alaska Railroad guide, 1923 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    Special guide for presidential party, including Herbert Hoover as Secretary of Commerce
  - Henry family genealogy, 1932 and undated (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Menu from luncheon in honor of President Warren G. Harding, 1923 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Newspaper clippings about Lou Henry Hoover, 1951, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - "Recollections of a Piece of Wood," poem by Lou Henry Hoover, 1930 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    Printed on White House stationery
- Photographs, circa 1850-1928
  - 1 print of a street scene in Waterloo, Iowa, undated (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - 1 print (portrait) of an unidentified young man in military uniform, undated (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - 1 print of Lou Henry and Jean Henry, undated (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - 8 prints of members of the Weed family, circa 1850-circa 1880 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    Includes photographs of Florence Weed (later Henry), Jennie, Eliza Barrett, Phineas, and Abigail Kimberly Howard
  - 15 prints of members of the Henry family, circa 1870-1910 (Box-folder 1: 14-16)
    Includes photographs of Charles Delano, Florence, Jean, Janet, Mary A., Jessie, W. D., and Addis Henry
  - 2 prints of Lou Henry Hoover as a child, circa 1875-1880 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - 2 prints of John and Nancy Wallace Scobey, 1880s (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - 2 prints of Lou Henry Hoover and Jean Henry in Yokohama, Japan, 1901 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - 1 print of Herbert Hoover, circa 1910 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - 4 prints of Lou Henry Hoover and Jean Henry hiking with others, 1924 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - 4 portraits of Lou Henry Hoover, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 22-24)
  - 23 prints of the Hoover's cabin on Rapidan river, Virginia (Camp Rapidan), circa 1929 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - 1 print of Herbert Hoover, 1930s (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - 1 portrait of Lou Henry Hoover in formal attire, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 27)
    Autographed to Susan Louise Dyer
  - 5 prints of Herbert and Lou Henry Hoover with their family, 1932-1939 (Box-folder 1: 28)